A Guide to the Philip S. Hench Walter Reed Yellow Fever Collection 1806-1995
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- CARD OF PEDRO RODRIGUEZ CAPOTE ('WITH SEASONS GREETINGS') N.D., PRINTED CARD (Box-folder 067-034)
- CARTOON BY HONORE DAUMIER ON YELLOW FEVER N.D., MAGAZINE CLIPPING (Box-folder 067-035)
- ENVELOPE ADDRESSED TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH N.D., TENVELOPE (Box-folder 067-036)
- INDEX CARDS TO PAMPHLETS IN YELLOW FEVER COLLECTION N.D., AMs (Box-folder 067-037)
- INDICES OF YELLOW FEVER PHOTOGRAPHS USED IN HENCH BOOK, ARTICLES, AND LECTURES N.D., *AN (Box-folder 067-038)
- INVITATIONS TO THE OPENING OF A PARK COMMEMORATING JESSE W. LAZEAR N.D., PRINTED CARDS (12) (Box-folder 067-039)
- MISCELLANEOUS NOTES RE 'HALL OF FAME,' YELLOW FEVER, ETC. N.D., *AN (Box-folder 067-040)
- MATERIALS RE: CLARA MAASS 1946-1952/ca., *TLS, TL (CC), TMs (CC), PAMPHLETS (Box-folder 067-041)
- MATERIALS RE: CLARA MAASS N.D., *TMs (CC), BROADSIDE (Box-folder 067-042)
- NOTES OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH RE: MR. SUTTON REED N.D., *AN (Box-folder 067-043)
- THE LATE MR. JOHN J. MORAN AND HIS CONNECTIONS IN THE CANAL ZONE N.D., TMs (CC) (Box-folder 067-044)
- NOTES AND BLANK CALENDAR PAPER N.D., *AN, PRINTED FORMS (Box-folder 067-045)
- PICTURES OF MEDAILLES N.D., PC (3) (Box-folder 067-046)
- OBITUARY OF EMILIE LAWRENCE REED N.D., NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 067-047)
- BOARD FROM BUILDING NUMBER ONE, CAMP LAZEAR SITE, HAVANA, CUBA 1948/ca., ARTIFACT (Box-folder 068-001)
- RECORDS OF THE ARMY MEDICAL SCHOOL 1898/10/02-1905/04/10, AMs (P), 2TM (P) (Box-folder 068-002)
- MISCELLANEOUS NUMBERED BINDERS MARKED 'YELLOW FEVER' N.D., BINDERS (5) (Box-folder 068-003)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF ATCHESON LAUGHLIN HENCH RE: WALTER REED "1946, 1964-1965", *ALS, TLS, TL (CC) (Box-folder 069-001)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF ATCHESON LAUGHLIN HENCH RE: WALTER REED 1966-1969, *ALS, TLS, TL (CC) (Box-folder 069-002)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF ATCHESON LAUGHLIN HENCH RE: WALTER REED 1970-1971, *ALS, TLS, TL (CC) (Box-folder 069-003)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF ATCHESON LAUGHLIN HENCH RE: WALTER REED 1972-1974, *ALS, TLS, TL (CC) (Box-folder 069-004)
- SOME OF THE EXPERIENCES OF JAMES C. REED AS A SOLDIER IN THE ARMY OF THE CONFEDERATE STATES 1920/ca., ARTICLES (P) (2) (Box-folder 069-005)
  WITH NOTES OF ATCHESON L. HENCH
- NOTES OF ATCHESON LAUGHLIN HENCH ON THE DINNER GIVEN IN HONOR OF MR. JOHN J. MORAN, ASSISTANT TO WALTER REED 1940/10/23, AMs (2), TMs (CC), NEWSPAPER (Box-folder 069-006)
  WITH ARTICLE ON DINNER IN COLLEGE TOPICS (UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA)
- ARTICLES AND NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS RE: THE WALTER REED YELLOW FEVER ARCHIVE ASSEMBLED BY PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH "1940-1942, 1966-1967", *NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS, MAGAZINES (Box-folder 069-007)
- CONQUERERS OF YELLOW FEVER, WALTER REED AND THE CONQUEST OF YELLOW FEVER BY PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH "1941, 1948", *ARTICLES (Box-folder 069-008)
- MEMORANDA OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH AND ATCHESON LAUGHLIN HENCH RE: WALTER REED 1946-1972, *AN, TN (Box-folder 069-009)
- UNVEILING OF THE BUST AND TABLET FOR WALTER REED, NEW YORK UNIVERSITY 1948/05/20, PROGRAMS (2) (Box-folder 069-010)
- ARTICLES BY AND ABOUT DR. WILLIAM B. BEAN, WALTER REED'S BIOGRAPHER "1967-1972, N.D.", *ARTICLES, NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (Box-folder 069-011)
- CARLOS FINLAY AND THE CARRIER OF DEATH 1971, ARTICLE (P) (Box-folder 069-012)
- DIPLOMA OF WALTER REED, DOCTOR OF MEDICINE, UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA 1869.07/01, DOCUMENT (Box-folder 070-001)
- FEVER CHART FOR JOHN J. MORAN 1900/12/24-1901/01/03, AMs (Box-folder 070-002)
- INFORMED CONSENT AGREEMENT BETWEEN ANTONIO BENIGNO AND WALTER REED 1900/11/26, TMsS (Box-folder 070-003)
- INFORMED CONSENT AGREEMENT BETWEEN ANTONIO BENIGNO AND WALTER REED 1900/11/26, TMs (Box-folder 070-004)
  ENGLISH TRANSLATION
- DIPLOMA, JESSE W. LAZEAR, DOCTOR OF MEDICINE, COLUMBIA COLLEGE 1892/06/08, DOCUMENT (Box-folder 070-005)
- DIPLOMA, JESSE. W. LAZEAR, BELLEVUE HOSPITAL 1894/01/01, DOCUMENT (Box-folder 070-006)
- DIPLOMA, JESSE W. LAZEAR, 1894, DOCUMENT (Box-folder 070-007)
- DIPLOMA, JESSE W. LAZEAR, BACHELOR OF ARTS, JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY 1889/06/13, DOCUMENT (Box-folder 070-008)
- MISCELLANEOUS DIPLOMAS AND CERTIFICATES, WALTER REED 1871-1872/ca., DOCUMENTS (4) (Box-folder 071-001)
- MISCELLANEOUS DIPLOMAS AND CERTIFICATES, WALTER REED N.D., DOCUMENTS (2) (Box-folder 071-002)
- ORDER OF FINLAY, BLOSSOM [EMILIE M.] REED, WITH AFFIXED MEDAL 1952/12/30, DOCUMENT IN FRAME, ARTIFACT (Box-folder 071-003)
- PAINTING OF UNIDENTIFIED HOUSE N.D., PAINTING IN FRAME (Box-folder 071-004)
- MAILING TUBES SENT TO WALTER REED 1902/ca., MAILING TUBES (2) (Box-folder 071-005)
- COLOR PRINT OF 'CONQUERORS OF YELLOW FEVER' BY DEAN CORNWELL N.D., PRINT (Box-folder 072-001)
- BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH OF DR. CHARLES E. FINLAY, JR., WITH PHOTOGRAPH N.D., BROADSIDE (Box-folder 072-002)
- BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH OF DR. CARLOS J. FINLAY, WITH PHOTOGRAPH N.D., BROADSIDE (Box-folder 072-003)
- ARTICLES RE: YELLOW FEVER 1900-1901, *NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (P) (Box-folder 072-004)
- HARPER'S WEEKLY 1898-1899, MAGAZINES (2) (Box-folder 072-005)
  WITH ARTICLES ON THE AMERICAN AND SPANISH PEACE COMMISSIONERS
- MISCELLANEOUS ARTICLES 1888-1889, *NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (P) (Box-folder 072-006)
- ARTICLES RE: CUBA, YELLOW FEVER, ETC. 1896-1901, *NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (Box-folder 072-007)
- SCRAPBOOK PROBABLY COMPILED BY BLOSSOM REED 1900-1901, SCRAPBOOK WITH CLIPPINGS, ENVELOPES, CARDS (Box-folder 072-008)
  THE SCRAPBOOK CONTAINS PHOTOGRAPHS FROM NEWSPAPERS AND MAGAZINES OF STAGE AND FILM ACTRESSES AS WELL AS OPERA AND CONCERT SINGERS. SEVERAL MEN ARE INCLUDED. PEOPLE REPRESENTED ARE VIOLA ALLEN, JULIA ARTHUR (CHENEY), ANNA HELD, MADGE LESSING (AUTOGRAPH AND ENVELOPE ADDRESSED TO MISS EMILIE LAWRENCE REED), JULIA MARLOWE (AUTOGRAPH), MAUDE ADAMS (AUTOGRAPH), MARGUERITE LEMON, OTIS SKINNER (AUTOGRAPH), VIRGINIA EARL, MARY MANNERING (AUTOGRAPH), VIRGINIA HARNED, JESSIE BARTLETT DAVIS, CAROLINE MISKEL, WILLIAM GILLETT, ALICE NIELSEN (AUTOGRAPH), EDWARD WILLARD (AUTOGRAPH) AND A NOTE BY ATCHESON HENCH.
- MISCELLANEOUS MATERIALS FROM ORIGINAL PHOTOGRAPHIC SERIES UNPROCESSED N.D., *AN, TN, PC (Box-folder 073)
- FLAG OF WALTER REED N.D., ARTIFACT (Box-folder 074)
  FROM BOX WITH ACCESSION NUMBER 8857-A
- SMOKESTACK FROM BUILDING NUMBER ONE, CAMP LAZEAR N.D., ARTIFACT (Box-folder 075)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - BIRTHPLACE OF WALTER REED; YELLOW FEVER EPIDEMIC SCENES, CAMP COLUMBIA, AND VARIOUS PERSONS (ARISTIDES AGRAMONTE - JAMES CARROLL) 1873-1947, PHOTOGRAPHS (Box-folder 076)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - CONQUERORS OF YELLOW FEVER BY DEAN CORNWELL, MODEL OF CAMP COLUMBIA, AND MISCELLANY 1898-1948, PHOTOGRAPHS (Box-folder 077)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - VARIOUS PERSONS (CARLOS FINLAY - JOHN R. KISSINGER) 1899-1948 (Box-folder 078)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - LAZEAR FAMILY; JESSE W. LAZEAR IN CUBA 1868-1906 (Box-folder 079)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - JESSE W. LAZEAR, JOHN J. MORAN, PLACE OF DEATH OF WALTER REED, VARIOUS PERSONS (ALBERT E. TRUBY) 1895-1948 (Box-folder 080)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - HAVANA AND ENVIRONS; HEADQUARTERS OF GENERAL FITZHUGH LEE 1898-1952 (Box-folder 081)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - QUEMADOS, AERIAL AND GENERAL VIEWS OF HAVANA LANDMARKS 1899-1952 (Box-folder 082)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - PINAR DEL RIO AND CAMP LAZEAR RESTORATION 1898-1953 (Box-folder 083)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - CAMP LAZEAR RESTORATION 1952 (Box-folder 084)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - CAMP LAZEAR RESTORATION 1952 (Box-folder 085)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - LAZEAR BUILDING (WASHINGTON AND JEFFERSON COLLEGE), REED MEMORIALS, REED AND LAZEAR FAMILIES 1940-1960 (Box-folder 086)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - WALTER REED, CARLOS FINLAY, JESSE W. LAZEAR MEMORIAL SITES, BUSTS, ILLUSTRATIONS; STILLS FROM YELLOW JACK AND JEZEBEL 1855-1968 (Box-folder 087)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - PRESENTATION OF DECORATIONS (ORDER OF FINLAY) TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH AND OTHERS; MISCELLANEOUS VIEWS OF HAVANA 1909-1951 (Box-folder 088)
- PHOTOGRAPHS OF LAS ANIMAS HOSPITAL, CIUDAD MILITAR (CAMP COLUMBIA), AERIAL VIEWS OF HAVANA 1900-1950 (Box-folder 089)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - FALSE AND ACTUAL SITES OF CAMP LAZEAR, HAVANA, CUBA 1900-1948 (Box-folder 090)
- PHOTOGRAPH - CAMP LAZEAR SITE, MAPS OF HAVANA AND VICINTY (QUEMADOS DE MARIANAO, CAMP COLUMBIA, HOSPITAL NUMBER ONE) 1860-1952 (Box-folder 091)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - COLONEL MANLY'S ALBUM (1898-1900); ATCHESON LAUGHLIN HENCH AND PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH, 1954 EUROPEAN TRIP; 2 PORTRAITS OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1898-1962 (Box-folder 092)
- PHOTOGRAPHS - CAMP LAZEAR MEMORIAL DEDICATION, DECEMBER 1952; AERIAL VIEWS OF HAVANA, STREET SCENES, ETC. 1879-1950 (Box-folder 093)
- PHOTOGRAPHS REED FAMILY, WALTER REED LETTERS, MABEL HOUSTON LAZEAR, MISCELLANEOUS HAVANA PHOTOS, CA. 1900, ETC. 1850-1966 (Box-folder 094)
- OVERSIZE PHOTOGRAPHS (Box-folder 095)
- NEGATIVES 1-96a (Box-folder 096)
- NEGATIVES 97-188 (Box-folder 097)
- NEGATIVES 189-294a (Box-folder 098)
- NEGATIVES 295-412 (Box-folder 099)
- NEGATIVES 412a-521 (Box-folder 100)
- NEGATIVES 522-572 (Box-folder 101)
- REPRINTS A (Box-folder 102)
- REPRINTS BALFOUR-BOYCE (Box-folder 103)
- REPRINTS BREINL-BURNETTE (Box-folder 104)
- REPRINTS CAIN-CARTER (Box-folder 105)
- REPRINTS CARTER (Box-folder 106)
- REPRINTS CARTER-CURRY (Box-folder 107)
- REPRINTS D,E (Box-folder 108)
- REPRINTS F (Box-folder 109)
- REPRINTS G (Box-folder 110)
- REPRINTS HAAGEN-HENCH (Box-folder 111)
- REPRINTS HEWES-HUTCHINSON (Box-folder 112)
- REPRINTS I, J, K (Box-folder 113)
- REPRINTS L (Box-folder 114)
- REPRINTS M (Box-folder 115)
- REPRINTS N (Box-folder 116)
- REPRINTS O-PHILIP (Box-folder 117)
- REPRINTS PICKELS-Q (Box-folder 118)
- REPRINTS RAMSEY-REED (Box-folder 119)
- REPRINTS REPORT-ROSS (Box-folder 120)
- REPRINTS ROSS (Box-folder 121)
- REPRINTS ROSS-RUSSELL (Box-folder 122)
- REPRINTS SANARELLI-SMITHBURN (Box-folder 123)
- REPRINTS SOPER-STERNBERG (Box-folder 124)
- REPRINTS STERNBERG-T (Box-folder 125)
- REPRINTS U, V, W (Box-folder 126)
- REPRINTS Y (Box-folder 127)
- REPRINTS MISCELLANEOUS - UNPROCESSED (Box-folder 128)
- REPRINTS - UNPROCESSED (Box-folder 129)
- MISCELLANEOUS AND DUPLICATE REPRINTS (Box-folder 130)
- MISCELLANEOUS AND DUPLICATE REPRINTS (Box-folder 131)
- MISCELLANEOUS AND DUPLICATE REPRINTS (Box-folder 132)
- MISCELLANEOUS AND DUPLICATE REPRINTS (Box-folder 133)
- MISCELLANEOUS AND DUPLICATE REPRINTS (Box-folder 134)
- MISCELLANEOUS AND DUPLICATE REPRINTS (Box-folder 135)
- MISCELLANEOUS AND DUPLICATE REPRINTS (Box-folder 136)
- LETTER FROM [ARISTIDES AGRAMONTE] TO J. C. HEMMETER 1913/02/02, TL (C) (Box-folder 137-001)
  INSCRIBED, NO DATE, BY PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO JOHN J. MORAN
- JOHN J. MORAN -- SOCIETY OF THE INCAS "1916, 1917, 1937", 3 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-002)
  PANAMA CANAL
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JOHN J. MORAN 1937, 2 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-003)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JOHN J. MORAN 1938, 4 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-004)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JOHN J. MORAN 1939, 5 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-005)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JOHN J. MORAN 1940, 14 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-006)
- PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH, TRANSLATIONS BY JOHN J. MORAN CONCERNING THE SITE OF CAMP LAZEAR [1940], 2 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-007)
  DEED AND DAYBOOK ENTRIES OF IGNACIO ROJAS
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JOHN J. MORAN 1941, 10 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-008)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JOHN J. MORAN 1942, 6 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-009)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JOHN J. MORAN 1943, 1 ITEM (Box-folder 137-010)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JOHN J. MORAN 1944, 4 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-011)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JOHN J. MORAN 1945, 3 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-012)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JOHN J. MORAN 1946, 4 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-013)
- LETTER FROM JEFFERSON RANDOLPH KEAN TO JOHN J. MORAN 1947/12/30, 1 ITEM, ALS (Box-folder 137-014)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JOHN J. MORAN 1947, 9 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-015)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH AND OTHER MATERIALS CONCERNING THE FOURTH INTERNATIONAL CONGRESS ON TROPICAL MEDICINE AND MALARIA 1947-1948, 36 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-016)
  INCLUDES CEREMONIES HONORING WALTER REED
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JOHN J. MORAN 1948, 2 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-017)
- LETTER FROM WALTER G. BAETZ TO JOHN J. MORAN 1949/03/26, 1 ITEM, TLS (Box-folder 137-018)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JOHN J. MORAN 1949, 5 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-019)
- LETTER FROM JEFFERSON RANDOLPH KEAN TO JOHN J. MORAN 1950/07/06, 1 ITEM, ALS (Box-folder 137-020)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH ELIDA C. MORAN 1950, 2 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-021)
- MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1951, 2 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-022)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH AND CONCERNING ELIDA C. MORAN 1953, 2 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-023)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH AND OTHER MATERIALS CONCERNING ELIDA C. MORAN AND JOHN J. MORAN 1954, 7 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-024)
- MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1955, 10 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-025)
- CORRESPONDENCE BETWEEN REED FAMILY, LANDON REED AND PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1956/08/22, 2 ITEMS, ALS WITH ENVELOPE (Box-folder 137-026)
- MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1956, 51 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-027)
- DICTAPHONE RECORDING, UNIDENTIFIED [INTERVIEW OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH WITH JAMES HANBERRY, ORANGEBURG, SOUTH CAROLINA?] [1956?], 1 ITEM (Box-folder 137-028)
- CORRESPONDENCE AND OTHER MATERIALS OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH CONCERNING GUSTAF E. LAMBERT AND ROGER POST AMES 1956-1959, 24 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-029)
- CORRESPONDENCE AND OTHER MATERIALS OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH RELATING TO THE WALTER REED MEMORIAL ASSOCIATION 1956-1963, 43 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-030)
- LETTERS FROM REED FAMILY, RALPH NADING HILL TO LANDON] REED 1957/01/09, 2 ITEMS, AL (CC) WITH ENVELOPE (Box-folder 137-031)
- MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1957, 7 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-032)
- LETTERS FROM REED FAMILY, PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH TO BLOSSOM [EMILIE M.] REED 1958/07/28, 1 ITEM, TLS (Box-folder 137-033)
- MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1958, 5 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-034)
- NOTES ON ENROLLMENT OF WALTER REED AT THE UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA 1959/04/15, AN (Box-folder 137-035)
  IN ATCHESON HENCHS HAND?
- MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1959, 10 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-036)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH CONCERNING THE DISPOSITION OF THE REED PAPERS 1959-1964, 7 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-037)
- LETTERS FROM REED FAMILY, LILLIAN BEAVER TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH AND MARY HENCH CONCERNING BLOSSOM [EMILIE M.] REED 1960, 6 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-038)
- MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1960, 4 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-039)
- REED FAMILY, BLOSSOM [EMILIE M.] REED TO PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH AND MARY HENCH DONALD W. MCINTIRE TO THE WASHINGTON POST "1961/03, 06/01", 3 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-040)
- MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1961, 3 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-041)
- MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE OF PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH 1962, 3 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-042)
- PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH, YELLOW FEVER BIBLIOGRAPHY AND NOTES ON WRITING HIS BOOK N.D., 2 ITEMS (Box-folder 137-043)
- WALTER REED - LETTER OF RECOMMENDATION FOR JOHN J. MORAN, ALDERMAN LIBRARY CONTROL FOLDER 1901/02/20, ALS, PHOTOCOPY (Box-folder 137-044)
- DRAMA AND WORK BEHIND A CANVAS 1941/07/20, NEWSPAPER ARTICLE (Box-folder 138-001)
- YELLOW JACK MET FATE FIFTY YEARS AGO 1950/06/25, NEWSPAPER ARTICLE (Box-folder 138-002)
- EMILIE LAWRENCE REED, NOTED ARMY DOCTORS WIDOW, DIES AT 94 [1950/07], NEWSPAPER ARTICLE (Box-folder 138-003)
  OBITUARY FOR EMILIE LAWRENCE REED
- GENERAL KEAN 1950/09/07, NEWSPAPER ARTICLE (Box-folder 138-004)
  OBITUARY FOR JEFFERSON RANDOLPH KEAN
- BRIG. GEN. J. R. KEAN, WITH WALTER REED IN CUBA, DIES HERE AT 90 GEN. KEAN RITES TOMORROW IN WALTER REED CHAPEL [1950/09], NEWSPAPER ARTICLE (C) (Box-folder 138-005)
  OBITUARY JEFFERSON RANDOLPH KEAN
- YELLOW JACK MEMORIAL FUND SOUGHT 1950/10/01, NEWSPAPER (C) (Box-folder 138-006)
- FINLAY 1953/12/03, NEWSPAPER ARTICLE (Box-folder 138-007)
- LOOK AND LISTEN WITH DONALD KIRKLEY 1955/01/12, NEWSPAPER ARTICLE (Box-folder 138-008)
  REVIEW OF YELLOW JACK
- WALTER REED GETS ORIGINAL NAME BACK 1960/01/07, NEWSPAPER ARTICLE (Box-folder 138-009)
- DEATHS ELSEWHERE: MURALIST DEAN CORNWELL 1960/12/07, NEWSPAPER ARTICLE (Box-folder 138-010)
  OBITUARY OF DEAN CORNWELL
- NON-VIRULENT, MALE MOSQUITOES COULD WIPE OUT ALL YELLOW FEVER 1960/12/23, NEWSPAPER ARTICLE (Box-folder 138-011)
- A YELLOW JACK HERO PASSES ON 1961/03/03, NEWSPAPER ARTICLE (Box-folder 138-012)
  OBITUARY FOR JAMES LEONARD HANBERRY
- TRIBUTE PAID TO WALTER REED, WALTER REED HONORED, YELLOW FEVER CURE, DEATHBED AID RECALLS YELLOW JACK DRAMA, PRAYER FOR TODAY "1961/05/25, N.D.", NEWSPAPER ARTICLES (Box-folder 138-013)
- CROWD SCENE AT HAVANA HARBOR 1902/05/07, [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-014)
- THE INCAS - PANAMA CANAL 1904, [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-015)
  INCLUDES PORTRAITS OF JOHN JL MORAN AND WILLIAM CRAWFORD GORGAS
- THE INCAS- PANAMA CANAL ca. 1904, [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-016)
  JOHN J. MORAN STANDING SECOND FROM LEFT
- JOHN J. MORAN IN PANAMA 1907/07/15, [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-017)
- SUNOCO OFFICES, HAVANA 1928/01/09, [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-018)
  JOHN J. MORAN SECOND FROM LEFT
- CAMP LAZEAR MEMORIAL ""PARQUE LAZEAR," N.D., [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-019)
  BRONZE PLAQUES FOR ""PARQUE LAZEAR"" AND ""CASETA NO. 1""
- CAMP LAZEAR MEMORIAL ""PARQUE LAZEAR," N.D., [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-020)
- CAMP LAZEAR MEMORIAL ""PARQUE LAZEAR," N.D., [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-021)
- CAMP LAZEAR MEMORIAL ""PARQUE LAZEAR," N.D., [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-022)
- LIONS CLUB OF CUBA MEMORIAL TO CARLOS J. FINLAY, MARIANAO N.D., [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-023)
- JOHN J. MORAN N.D., [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-024)
- JOHN J. MORAN N.D., [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-025)
- JOHN J. MORAN N.D., [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-026)
- JOHN J. MORAN N.D., [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-027)
- JOHN J. MORAN N.D., [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-028)
- JOHN J. MORAN N.D., [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-029)
- MEDAL OF HONOR AWARDED TO JOHN J. MORAN N.D., [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 138-030)
- THE INSIDE HISTORY OF A GREAT MEDICAL DISCOVERY 1915/12, REPRINT (Box-folder 138-031)
- WALTER REED IN MINNESOTA 1943/09, REPRINT (Box-folder 138-032)
- CONQUERORS OF YELLOW FEVER 1941/06/02, REPRINT (Box-folder 138-033)
- CONQUERORS OF YELLOW FEVER 1941/12/10, REPRINT (Box-folder 138-034)
- A CHRONICLE OF WALTER REEDS INTERNSHIPS AND PUBLIC HEALTH TRAINING 1949/04-06, REPRINT (Box-folder 138-035)
- JUSTIFICACION DE TOPES DE COLLANTES 1954, PUBLICATION (Box-folder 138-036)
- UNVEILING OF THE BUST AND TABLET FOR WALTER REED 1948/05/20, PUBLICATION (Box-folder 138-037)
- MOMORIES OF AN IMMORTAL 1948/09, REPRINT (Box-folder 138-038)
- THE ETIOLOGY OF YELLOW FEVER - A PRELIMINARY NOTE 1900/10/22-26, REPRINT (Box-folder 138-039)
- THE PROPAGATION OF YELLOW FEVER: OBSERVATION BASED ON RECENT RESEARCHES, THE PREVENTION OF YELLOW FEVER "1901/04/24,27 1901/09/16", REPRINT (Box-folder 138-040)
- THE ETIOLOGY OF YELLOW FEVER - A SUPPLEMENTAL NOTE 1902/02/22, REPRINT (Box-folder 138-041)
- REVISTA DE LA SOCIEDAD CUBANA DE HISTORIA DE LA MEDICINA 1958/10-12, PUBLICATION (Box-folder 138-042)
  ISSUE DEVOTED TO CARLOS J. FINLAY
- REVISTA DE LA SOCIEDAD CUBANA DE HISTORIA DE LA MEDICINA 1959/04-06, PUBLICATION (Box-folder 138-043)
  INCLUDES ARTICLE BY PEDRO NOGUEIRA UNA ACLARACION A UN EPISODIO DE LA HISTORIA DE LA FIEBRE AMARILLA
- OUR SUN 1931/12, PUBLICATION (Box-folder 138-044)
  INCLUDES ARTICLE ON JOHN J. MORAN
- WASHINGTON AND JEFFERSON COLLEGE ALUMNI BULLETIN 1956/10, PUBLICATION (Box-folder 138-045)
  COVER PHOTOGRAPH OF JESSE W. LAZEAR CHEMISTRY HALL
- THE DEVELOPMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH MEDICINE IN MINNESOTA 1936, REPRINT (Box-folder 138-046)
- A PHILATELIC TALE OF YELLOW FEVER 1940, REPRINT (Box-folder 138-047)
- INVENTORY OF WALTER REED AND REED FAMILY MATERIAL TRANSFERRED TO THE HEALTH SCIENCES LIBRARY FROM ALDERMAN LIBRARY SPECIAL COLLECTIONS N.D., 8 ITEMS (Box-folder 139-001)
  INCLUDES ALDERMAN LIBRARY ACCESSION NUMBERS
- HOSPITAL FLAG FROM CAMP LAZEAR CUBA 1900/ca., ARTIFACT (Box-folder 139-002)
  RED CROSS, FORMERLY ACCESSION 8560
- WILLIAM H. MCGUFFEY - CLASS OF MORAL PHILOSOPHY, UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA INCLUDES CHRISTOPHER REED AND JAMES CLAYTON REED 1868, [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 139-003)
- WALTER REED ca. 1875, [PHOTOGRAPH] (Box-folder 139-004)
- WALTER REED - CHEMISTRY NOTEBOOK KEPT AT THE UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA 1868-1869, 1 BOUND VOLUME, ca. 190 PAGES (Box-folder 139-005)
  INCLUDES SOME NOTES OF JAMES REED. FORMERLY ACCESSION 2811-D
- WALTER REED - DIPLOMA FROM THE UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA 1869/07/01, 1 ITEM, PHOTOSTAT (Box-folder 139-006)
- LETTER FROM WALTER REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1874/04/13, ALS (PHOTOSTAT) (Box-folder 139-007)
  FORMERLY ACCESSION 8931. ORIGINAL IN THE LIBRARY OF VIRGINIA
- LETTER FROM WALTER REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1877/06/06, ALS (Box-folder 139-008)
  FORMERLY ACCESSION 8931
- PHILIP SHOWALTER HENCH - MATERIALS CONCERNING THE YELLOW FEVER EPIDEMIC OF 1878 IN MEMPHIS TENNESSEE 1879 AND N.D., 2 ITEMS (Box-folder 139-009)
- LETTER FROM WALTER REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1882/09/21, ALS (Box-folder 139-010)
- LETTER FROM WALTER REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1883/04/02, ALS (Box-folder 139-011)
- LETTER FROM WALTER REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1889/09/22, ALS (Box-folder 139-012)
- LETTER FROM W. G. STARR TO LEMUEL S. REED [1889]/10/21, ALS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-013)
  FORMERLY ACCESSION 8931-C
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1889/10/31, ALS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-014)
- LETTER FROM WALTER REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1889/11/04, ALS (Box-folder 139-015)
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1889/11/09, ALS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-016)
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1890/02/17, APCS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-017)
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1890/05/06, APCS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-018)
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1890/06/05, ALS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-019)
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1890/06/16, APCS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-020)
  FORMERLY ACCESSION 8932-C
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1890/06/20, APCS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-021)
  FORMERLY 8931-C
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1890/08/21, APCS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-022)
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1890/12/01, ALS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-023)
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1890/12/19, ALS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-024)
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1891/01/31, ALS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-025)
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1891/03/06, APCS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-026)
- LETTER FROM WALTER REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1892/02/28, ALS (Box-folder 139-027)
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1892/08/12, ALS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-028)
- LETTER FROM WALTER REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1892/11/28, ALS (Box-folder 139-029)
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1893/03/08, ALS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-030)
- LETTER FROM LEMUEL S. REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1893/03/25, ALS WITH TRANSCRIPTION (Box-folder 139-031)
- LETTER FROM WALTER REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1893/04/07, ALS (Box-folder 140-001)
- LETTER FROM WALTER REED TO LAURA REED BLINCOE 1893/11/14, ALS (PHOTOSTAT) (Box-folder 140-002)
  FORMERLY ACCESSION 8931. ORIGINAL IN LIBRARY OF VIRGINIA.